<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>org-mode on egli.dev</title>
    <link>http://egli.dev/tags/org-mode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in org-mode on egli.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://egli.dev/tags/org-mode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick and dirty PDF reports for Plain Text Accounting</title>
      <link>http://egli.dev/posts/quick-and-dirty-pdf-reports-for-plain-text-accounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egli.dev/posts/quick-and-dirty-pdf-reports-for-plain-text-accounting/</guid>
      <description>Say you want to hand out financial reports (such as a balance sheet and an income statement) to a non-techie someone. Most likely that means handing out the statements on paper. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m doing Plain Text Accounting, what is an easy way to generate decent looking output on paper?
hledger has two convenient commands to generate a balance sheet and an income statement. Let&amp;rsquo;s use the demo.journal from the hledger web site as an example for this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using org-mode for meeting minutes</title>
      <link>http://egli.dev/posts/using-org-mode-for-meeting-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 15:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egli.dev/posts/using-org-mode-for-meeting-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Due to an unfortunate series of events, I&amp;rsquo;m back in the business of taking meeting minutes. After a meeting I want to know:
 what was discussed what was decided what are the next tasks and who is taking care of them  Well, I thought, there is nothing really too hard if you have org-mode in your tool chest. I searched for some prior art and found an old thread on the mailing list where this very issue is discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulltext Search in org-mode</title>
      <link>http://egli.dev/posts/fulltext-search-in-org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 13:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egli.dev/posts/fulltext-search-in-org-mode/</guid>
      <description>Quite often I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find something that I jotted down in one of my many org-mode files somewhere. This usually amounts to something like
M-x rgreg RET foo RET *.org RET ~/ RET Then I wait until grep has finished rummaging trough my home directory. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if there was something like fulltext search for org-mode files, i.e. if there was a tool that would index all my files and provide for a fast search capability?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
